夜の森は漆黒の闇に包まれていた
潘丽宝：夜晚的森林被漆黑的暗影所笼罩
The forest at night was wrapped in jet-black darkness.
そんな、一寸先も見えぬほどの闇の中を、
潘丽宝：在那伸手不见五指的黑暗中，
In that darkness where one couldn't see an inch ahead,
一人の少女が家路を急いでいる
潘丽宝：一名少女正急匆匆地赶在回家的路上
a girl was rushing home.
すると、どこからか、不思議な音が聞こえてくる
潘丽宝：突然，不知从何处，传来了不可思议的声音
Then, from somewhere, a strange sound was heard.
チリーン、チリーン
潘丽宝：叮铃，叮铃
Chirin, chirin.
少女は空耳かと、耳を澄ます
潘丽宝：少女以为是幻听，侧耳倾听
Thinking she imagined it, the girl strained her ears.
しかし、鈴のようなその音は、
潘丽宝：可是，那铃铛般的声音，
However, that bell-like sound was
間違いなく少女の後を追いかけてくるのだ
潘丽宝：确实是在身后追逐着少女而来
undoubtedly chasing after her.
チリーン、チリーン
潘丽宝：叮铃，叮铃
Chirin, chirin.
音から逃れようと走り出すと、
潘丽宝：想要逃离声音而奔跑起来，
When she started running to escape the sound,
鈴の音は次第に近く、速くなっていく
潘丽宝：铃声却逐渐逼近，越来越快
the ringing got closer and faster.
チリーン、チリーン
潘丽宝：叮铃，叮铃
Chirin, chirin.
チリーン、チリーン、チリーン
潘丽宝：叮铃，叮铃，叮铃
Chirin, chirin, chirin.
ついには音は、真後ろまで迫り
潘丽宝：终于，声音逼近到了正后方
Finally, the sound closed in right behind her.
耐え切れなくなった少女が振り返ると
潘丽宝：无法忍受的少女回过头一看
Unable to bear it any longer, the girl turned around...
ぎゃあああああ！
：呀啊啊啊啊啊！
Gyaaaaaah!
君たち、いつまで起きてんの？
珂朵莉：你们几个，要醒到什么时候啊？
You guys, how long are you going to stay up?
なんだ、クトリか
潘丽宝：什么嘛，是珂朵莉啊
Oh, it's just Chtholly.
こんな真夜中まで騒いで、一体何をやってるの？
珂朵莉：吵闹到这种深更半夜，到底在搞什么啊？
Making all this noise in the middle of the night, what on earth are you doing?
怪談だぞ
可蓉：是怪谈哦
It's ghost stories!
怪談？
珂朵莉：怪谈？
Ghost stories?
私たちは今宵
潘丽宝：我们要在今晚
Tonight, we represent...
伝説のお化けを呼び出すのだ
潘丽宝：我们要召唤传说中的妖怪
...we are summoning the legendary monster!
終末なにしてますか？忙しいですか？救ってもらっていいですか？
珂朵莉：末日时在做什么？有没有空？可以来拯救吗？
What do you do at the end of the world? Are you busy? Will you save us?
スペシャルオーディオドラマ
珂朵莉：特别广播剧
Special Audio Drama
「妖精倉庫怪談物語」
潘丽宝：《妖精仓库怪谈物语》
"Fairy Warehouse Ghost Stories"
怪談で伝説のお化けを呼び出す？
珂朵莉：用怪谈召唤传说中的妖怪？
Summoning a legendary monster with ghost stories?
まあ、実は今日、図書室で面白い本を見つけたのだ
潘丽宝：嘛，其实是今天在图书室发现了一本有趣的书
Well, actually, I found an interesting book in the library today.
68番島七不思議
珂朵莉：《68号岛七大不可思议》
"The Seven Mysteries of Island No. 68"
よくある子供向けの怪談物語集じゃない
珂朵莉：这不是常见的儿童向怪谈故事集嘛
Isn't this just a common ghost story collection for kids?
ふむ、確かに怪談自体は子供騙しだ
潘丽宝：嗯，确实怪谈本身是骗小孩的
Hmm, indeed, the ghost stories themselves are childish tricks.
ティアットとラキシュは怖がってたけどな
可蓉：不过缇亚忒和菈琪旭可是怕得不行呢
Tiat and Lakhesh were scared though.
こ、怖かったわけじゃないよ！
缇亚忒：才、才没有害怕呢！
I-I wasn't scared!
突然扉が開いたからびっくりしただけだもん！
缇亚忒：只是因为门突然打开被吓了一跳而已！
I was just surprised because the door opened suddenly!
ね、ラキシュ
缇亚忒：对吧，菈琪旭
Right, Lakhesh?
あ、うん
菈琪旭：啊，嗯
Ah, yeah.
で、でも、クトリ先輩が言うように、
菈琪旭：但是，就像珂朵莉前辈说的，
Bu, but, like Chtholly-senpai said,
今日はもう遅いからおしまいにした方が……
菈琪旭：今天已经很晚了，还是结束比较……
it's late, so maybe we should stop...
だめだ！儀式はすでに始まってしまったのだから
潘丽宝：不行！因为仪式已经开始了
No! Because the ritual has already begun!
儀式？
珂朵莉：仪式？
Ritual?
それで床に不気味な蝋燭が並べてあるの？
珂朵莉：所以地板上才摆着令人毛骨悚然的蜡烛吗？
Is that why these eerie candles are lined up on the floor?
そう。この本によれば、7つの怪談を一つずつ語り、
潘丽宝：没错。根据这本书所写，每讲完七个怪谈中的一个，
Yes. According to this book, we tell seven ghost stories one by one,
その度に蝋燭を一つずつ消していく
潘丽宝：就要熄灭一根蜡烛
and blow out a candle after each one.
もう5つ消したぞ
可蓉：已经灭了5根了哦
We've already put out five.
3つ目の時、ラキシュってば読みながら泣きそうになってたよね
可蓉：第3个的时候，菈琪旭边读边快要哭出来了呢
During the third one, Lakhesh looked like she was about to cry while reading.
そ、そういうティアットだって、口裂けマダムの話でおしっこ漏らしそうに……
菈琪旭：那、那缇亚忒不也是，听裂口夫人的故事时差点尿出……
W-Well, Tiat, you also almost peed yourself during the Slit-Mouthed Madame story...
わああああああ！
缇亚忒：哇啊啊啊啊啊啊！
Waaaaah!
なんだ、屋根の上に猫がいるぞ
缇亚忒：怎么回事，屋顶上有猫哦
What! There's a cat on the roof.
にゃーお
：喵呜——
Meow.
猫、可愛いな、あはははは
缇亚忒：猫咪，真可爱啊，啊哈哈哈哈
Cats are cute, ahaha.
誤魔化し方が雑すぎる
珂朵莉：敷衍得太随便了吧
That was a terrible attempt at covering it up.
そして、7本全ての蝋燭を消した時、伝説のお化けが現れるのだ
潘丽宝：然后，当7根蜡烛全部熄灭时，传说中的妖怪就会出现
And when all seven candles are extinguished, the legendary monster will appear!
伝説のお化け？
珂朵莉：传说中的妖怪？
Legendary monster?
何よそれ
珂朵莉：那是什么啊
What's that?
わからん
潘丽宝：不知道
I don't know.
わからないのに呼び出すの？
珂朵莉：不知道还要召唤吗？
You're summoning it without knowing what it is?
きっとこの世のものとは思えぬほど、
潘丽宝：肯定是让人无法觉得是这世间之物，
I'm sure it's a muddy,
ドロドロで禍々しいお化けに違いない
潘丽宝：黏糊糊又不祥的妖怪
ominous monster unlike anything in this world.
未知の恐怖！
可蓉：未知的恐怖！
Unknown terror!
それに途中でやめたら、不幸になる
潘丽宝：而且如果半途而废的话，会变得不幸的
Besides, if we stop halfway, we'll be cursed with misfortune.
そうなの？
缇亚忒：是那样吗？
Really?
かもしれない
潘丽宝：也许吧
Maybe.
嘘なの？
菈琪旭：骗人的吗？
Is that a lie?
とにかく我々は、もはや立ち止まることはできないのだ
潘丽宝：总之我们，已经无法停下脚步了
Anyway, we can no longer turn back!
だー！
可蓉：哒——！
Daaah!
立ち止まろうよ、二人とも
菈琪旭：停下来吧，你们两个
Stop right there, both of you.
しょうがないな
珂朵莉：真拿你们没办法
Good grief.
その代わり、私が最後まで立ち会うのが条件よ。いいわね？
珂朵莉：取而代之的是，我要陪同到最后作为条件。可以吧？
Instead, I'll stay with you until the end. Is that okay?
はーい
：好——
Okaaaay.
は、こうでもしなきゃ、この子たち絶対寝ないもんな
珂朵莉：不这样的话，这些孩子绝对不会睡的吧
If we don't do this, these kids definitely won't sleep.
じゃあ、6つ目のお話を始めるぞ
可蓉：那么，开始讲第6个故事了哦
Alright, I'll start the 6th story.
え？コロンが？
珂朵莉：诶？可蓉讲？
Eh? Collon is telling it?
もちろん！
可蓉：当然！
Of course!
昔々、ある古いお屋敷での出来事
可蓉：很久很久以前，发生在某个古老宅邸里的事
Once upon a time, in a certain old mansion...
お屋敷には、仲妻良じなリュカントロポスの夫婦が住んでいました
可蓉：宅邸里住着一对嗯爱的狼人族夫妇
A hilarious (harmonious) Lycanthropos couple lived in the mansion.
仲妻良じ？
珂朵莉：嗯爱？
Hilarious? (Harmonious?)
ある日、庭師のインプが奥様を拐かし、
可蓉：有一天，鬼族庭院师拐骗了夫人，
One day, the Imp gardener abducted the wife,
二人は過ちを犯してしまいました
可蓉：两人犯下了过错
and the two committed a mistake.
なあクトリ、過ちって何したの？
可蓉：呐珂朵莉，犯下过错是做了什么？
Hey Chtholly, what kind of mistake did they make?
え？えっと、そりゃ君、男と女がアレしてアレのアレよ
珂朵莉：诶？那个，那个嘛，就是男人和女人那个那个之后那个啦
Eh? Um, well, you know, when a man and a woman do that and that...
あれ？
可蓉：那个？
That?
だから、雄しべと雌しべに別の雄しべが横入りしたっていうか
珂朵莉：所以说，就是雄蕊和雌蕊之间有别的雄蕊插进来了……
So, it's like another stamen cut in between a stamen and a pistil...
よくわかんない
可蓉：完全听不懂
I don't get it.
コロンはまだ知らなくていいことだよ
菈琪旭：这是可蓉还不需要知道的事情哦
It's something Collon doesn't need to know yet.
ラキシュ、君何を知ってるの？
珂朵莉：菈琪旭，你知道些什么啊？
Lakhesh, what do you know?
んー、まいっか
可蓉：嗯——算啦
Hmm, whatever.
激昂した旦那は、包丁を持ち出しインプを、
可蓉：激怒的丈夫拿出了菜刀，
The enraged husband took out a kitchen knife
キッタンバッタンに切り裂いてしまった
可蓉：把鬼族咔嚓咔嚓地砍成了碎片
and chopped the Imp into pieces—chop, chop!
キッタンバッタン？
缇亚忒：咔嚓咔嚓？
Chop, chop?
お屋敷に響き渡る、生きたまま切り裂かれたインプの、団地妻
可蓉：响彻宅邸的，被活生生砍碎的鬼族的，“团地妻”（人妻）
Echoing through the mansion was the "Apartment Wife" of the Imp being sliced alive.
団地……
珂朵莉：团地……
Apartment...
断末魔だ
潘丽宝：是“断末魔”
It's "Danmatsuma".
そして、旦那はインプの死体を湖に投げ捨てました
可蓉：然后，丈夫把鬼族的尸体扔进了湖里
Then, the husband threw the Imp's corpse into the lake.
うわ、結構えげつない
珂朵莉：哇，还挺残酷的
Wow, that's pretty nasty.
仕方ないです
菈琪旭：这也是没办法的事
It can't be helped.
この場合、人妻に手を出したインプが100パーセント悪いですから
菈琪旭：这种情况下，对人妻出手的鬼族是百分之百的错
In this case, the Imp who messed with a married woman is 100% at fault.
多くの浮遊島の法律で淫行は犯罪で、
菈琪旭：在许多悬浮岛的法律中通奸是犯罪，
In the laws of many floating islands, adultery is a crime,
島によっては死刑になることもあるんですよ
菈琪旭：有些岛甚至会判死刑哦
and on some islands, it can even result in the death penalty.
って、君は本当に何を知ってるの？
珂朵莉：话说，你到底都知道些什么啊？
Wait, what exactly do you know?
それからというもの、お屋敷には毎晩、インプの生麦が現れ
可蓉：从那以后，宅邸里每晚都会出现鬼族的“生麦”
Ever since then, every night, the Imp's "Raw Wheat" appears in the mansion...
生首
潘丽宝：是生首（人头）
Severed head.
辺りを舐め回しながら、誰かを探し続けた
可蓉：一边到处舔舐着，一边寻找着某人
...licking everything around it, searching for someone.
ペロリ、ペロリ、どこだ、どこだ！
可蓉：吸溜，吸溜，在哪里，在哪里！
Lick, lick... Where is it... Where is it?!
ペロリ
可蓉：吸溜
Lick.
うむ、頬を舐められた
潘丽宝：唔姆，脸颊被舔了
Umm. My cheek was licked.
こいつじゃない、ペロリ
可蓉：不是这家伙，吸溜
Not this one. Lick.
あか、コロン、耳たぶはやめて
珂朵莉：啊哈，可蓉，别舔耳垂
Aha, Collon, stop licking my earlobes.
こいつではない、ペロリ
可蓉：也不是这家伙，吸溜
Not this one either. Lick.
うわっ
缇亚忒：哇
Ugh.
涎が、鼻に、は、は、は
缇亚忒：口水，进鼻子里了，哈、哈、哈
Drool... in my nose... Ha... Ha... Ha...
お前か！
可蓉：是你吗！
Is it you?!
はっくしゅん！
缇亚忒：阿嚏！
Achoo!
べちっ
缇亚忒：啪叽
Splat.
うわ、こっちまで飛んできたぞ
潘丽宝：哇，都飞到这边来了
Whoa, it flew all the way over here.
鼻紙鼻紙、ほら、ちゃんと噛んで
珂朵莉：纸巾纸巾，来，好好擤出来
Tissue, tissue. Here, blow properly.
ちーん
缇亚忒：（擤鼻涕声）
(Blowing nose)
せっかくのオチが台無し
可蓉：难得的结局全毁了
The punchline is ruined.
うーん、コロンが読み手だと、全然怖くならないな
潘丽宝：唔，可蓉来讲的话，完全不可怕呢
Hmm, when Collon reads it, it's not scary at all.
うん、ちぇっ
可蓉：嗯，切
Yeah. Tch.
蝋燭消そっと
可蓉：把蜡烛灭了吧
I'll blow out the candle.
ふう
可蓉：呼——
Foo.
消えた
潘丽宝：灭了
It's out.
ろ、蝋燭一本になると、結構暗くなるね
菈琪旭：蜡、蜡烛只剩下一根的话，变得相当暗了呢
W-When there's only one candle left, it gets pretty dark.
うん、炎の揺らめきが、壁に影を作ってなんだか不気味
缇亚忒：嗯，火焰的摇曳在墙上投下影子，总觉得好阴森
Yeah. The flickering flame casts shadows on the wall... it's kind of creepy.
きゃ！何！？
缇亚忒：呀！什么！？
Kya! What?!
どうしたのティアット、急に抱きついてきて
珂朵莉：怎么了缇亚忒，突然抱过来
What's wrong, Tiat? Hugging me all of a sudden.
風で窓が揺れただけよ
珂朵莉：只是风把窗户吹得晃了一下而已
It's just the wind shaking the window.
あ、窓、そっか
缇亚忒：啊，窗户，这样啊
Oh, the window. I see.
怖いのカ？
可蓉：害怕了吗？
Are you scared?
ち、違うよ、怖くなんかないよ。
缇亚忒：不、不是啦，才没有害怕呢。
N-No way, I'm not scared.
私はもう大人なんだから
缇亚忒：我已经是个大人了
I'm an adult already.
うらめしや
潘丽宝：我好恨啊
Urameshiya...
きゃあああああ！
缇亚忒：呀啊啊啊啊啊！
Kyaaaaaah!
壁の絵が勝手に落ちた！
缇亚忒：墙上的画自己掉了！
The picture on the wall fell by itself!
あ、時計が勝手に！
缇亚忒：啊，钟表自己！
Ah, the clock is...!
フクロウが！
缇亚忒：猫头鹰！
The owl!
にゃーにゃー
缇亚忒：喵——喵——
Meow, meow.
やっぱり怖いんだな
潘丽宝：果然还是害怕了啊
So you are scared.
怖くなんかニャイ！
缇亚忒：才没害怕喵！
I'm n-nyot scared!
あ、ラキシュは？
可蓉：啊，菈琪旭呢？
Ah, where's Lakhesh?
そういえばいないわね
珂朵莉：说起来不在呢
Come to think of it, she's gone.
ブルブルブルブル……
菈琪旭：瑟瑟发抖瑟瑟发抖……
Rattling and rattling...
をあ！お布団が震えてるぞ！
可蓉：哇啊！被子在震动！
Whoa! The quilt is chilling!
ひい！ポルターガイスト……
菈琪旭：噫……骚灵现象……
Yee! Poltergeist...
そんなわけないでしょ……
珂朵莉：怎么可能有那种事……
No way that's real...
ほっ
珂朵莉：喝
Hup.
何してるの、ラキシュ
珂朵莉：在干什么呢，菈琪旭
What are you doing, Lakhesh?
あ、あの、もう寝る時間なので、おやすみなさい
菈琪旭：啊，那个，已经到睡觉时间了，晚安
Uh, um, it's time to sleep, so good night.
ちっ
潘丽宝：切
Tch.
狸寝入りと決め込んだか
潘丽宝：决定装睡了吗
Decided to play possum, huh?
じゃ、じゃあ、私も……
缇亚忒：那、那我也……
Th-Then, I'll...
ふん
潘丽宝：呼嗯
Hmm.
パ、パニバル、て、話して……
缇亚忒：和潘、潘丽宝说说话……
...t-talk to Pannibal...
ふん、もう大人なティアットが逃げ出したりしないだろうな
潘丽宝：哼，已经是大人的缇亚忒，应该不会逃跑吧
Hmph. Since Tiat is an adult now, she wouldn't run away, right?
あ、当たり前よ！私は成体妖精兵なんだから！
缇亚忒：那、那是当然的！我可是成体妖精兵啊！
O-Of course! I'm an adult fairy soldier!
ティアット、気合いと根性だぞ！
可蓉：缇亚忒，拿出气势和毅力来！
Tiat, show some guts and spirit!
じゃあ、ラストはクトリ先輩に
潘丽宝：那么，最后一个就交给珂朵莉前辈
Well then, let's have Chtholly-senpai handle the last one.
うお、私が読むの？
珂朵莉：呜哇，我来读吗？
Whoa, I have to read it?
ああ、セニオリスを従える最強の妖精兵の力というやつを、
潘丽宝：啊，一定要让我们见识一下，驾驭瑟尼欧里斯的最强妖精兵的力量
Yes. We definitely want you to show us the power of the strongest fairy soldier
ぜひ我々に見せてほしい
潘丽宝：一定要让我们见识一下
who wields Seniorious.
うわー、クトリ先輩かっこいい！
缇亚忒：哇——珂朵莉前辈好帅！
Wow, Chtholly-senpai is so cool!
それってこんなところで発揮するものじゃないと思うけど、
珂朵莉：我觉得那种力量不是在这种地方发挥的，
I don't think that's the kind of power to show off here,
まあささっと読んでささっと寝かせちゃうか
珂朵莉：算了，赶紧读完赶紧让她们睡觉吧
but fine. I'll read it quickly so they can go to sleep.
ねえ、君たちは知ってるかな？妖精倉庫の裏山の奥に
珂朵莉：呐，你们知道吗？在妖精仓库的后山深处
Hey, do you girls know? Deep in the mountains behind the Fairy Warehouse...
とても大きなハクモクレンの木があるの
珂朵莉：有一棵非常巨大的白木莲树
...there's a very large White Magnolia tree.
なぜ本を開かないんだ？
潘丽宝：为什么不打开书？
Why aren't you opening the book?
クトリ先輩、7つ目のお話を知ってるんですか？
缇亚忒：珂朵莉前辈，难道你知道第7个故事吗？
Chtholly-senpai, do you know the 7th story?
うふふ
珂朵莉：呵呵
Ufufu.
うふふ、なんかクトリ先輩がいつもと違うよ
菈琪旭：感觉珂朵莉前辈和平时不一样哦
Huhh. Chtholly-senpai seems different than usual.
そのハクモクレンは、春になると真っ白な花がたくさん咲いて、
珂朵莉：那棵白木莲，一到了春天就会开满纯白的花，
That White Magnolia tree blooms with many pure white flowers in the spring.
とっても綺麗なの
珂朵莉：非常漂亮
It's very beautiful.
でもね、綺麗すぎたのがいけなかった
珂朵莉：但是呢，太漂亮也是一种罪过
But, it was too beautiful for its own good.
私がまだ小さかった頃、その木で首吊り自殺があったの
珂朵莉：在我还小的时候，有人在那棵树上上吊自杀了
When I was still little, someone committed suicide by hanging from that tree.
ひえー、自殺か
缇亚忒：噫——自杀啊
Eek, suicide?
変なの
可蓉：真奇怪
Strange.
それからその木、出るんですって
珂朵莉：从那以后，那棵树，据说会出现哦
Ever since then... it appears.
で、で、で、出るってつまり
缇亚忒：出、出、出、出现也就是说
A-A-A-Appears means...
うん
珂朵莉：嗯
Yup.
へえ！
缇亚忒：诶！
Eek!
それで私とレンとアイセアは、興味本位で真夜中に
珂朵莉：于是我和奈芙莲还有艾瑟雅，出于好奇心，
So Ren, Ithea, and I decided to go on a test of courage
肝試しに出かけることにしたの
珂朵莉：决定在深夜去试胆
in the middle of the night, just out of curiosity.
うわあ、肝試し良いな
可蓉：哇，试胆真好啊
Wow, a test of courage sounds fun.
うむ、是非我々も……
潘丽宝：唔姆，务必让我们也……
Indeed, we should also...
やらなくていい！
：不用做！
No, we don't!
その日は冬の終わりで、まだ雪が少し残ってて、
珂朵莉：我记得那是在冬末，还残留着一点积雪，
It was the end of winter. I remember there was still some snow left,
風が冷たかったのを覚えてる
珂朵莉：风很冷
and the wind was cold.
あ、ラキシュいつの間に隣に
缇亚忒：啊，菈琪旭什么时候到我旁边的
Ah, Lakhesh, when did you get next to me?
だって、布団が恋しくて
菈琪旭：因为，我想念被窝了
Because... I missed my quilt.
布団の中から言われてもな
潘丽宝：就算你在被窝里这么说也……
Coming from inside the quilt...
沼地をしばらく行くと、ハクモクレンの木が見えてきた
珂朵莉：穿过沼泽走了一会儿，就看见了白木莲树
After walking through the swamp for a while, the White Magnolia tree came into view.
そうしたらアイセアが、「一つだけ花が咲いてる」って言うのよ
珂朵莉：然后艾瑟雅说，“有一朵花开了哦”
Then Ithea said, "There's just one flower blooming."
目を凝らしてみると、確かに一つだけ花が咲いてた
珂朵莉：我定睛一看，确实只开了一朵花
I strained my eyes and saw that indeed, only one flower was blooming.
そして、花のついた枝だけ、しり、しりと揺れていた
珂朵莉：而且，只有那根长着花的树枝，嘎吱、嘎吱地摇晃着
And only the branch with the flower was creaking, creaking as it swayed.
あ、ハクモクレンて、冬の花だっけ？
缇亚忒：啊，白木莲，是冬天的花吗？
Ah, is the White Magnolia a winter flower?
うん、木蓮は春先きの花だから、冬の終わりならそういうこともあるだろうな
潘丽宝：嗯，木莲是早春的花，冬末的话也是有可能开的吧
Yeah, magnolias are early spring flowers, so it's possible at the end of winter.
そっか
缇亚忒：这样啊，
I see.
『気の早い花がいたもんっすね』
珂朵莉：“有个性急的花呢”
"Must have been an impatient flower."
そうアイセアが笑うから、私も安心してた
珂朵莉：因为艾瑟雅那样笑了，我也安心了
Since Ithea laughed like that, I felt relieved too.
でもなぜかレンだけは、それ以上近づきたがらなかったの
珂朵莉：但是不知为何只有莲，不愿意再靠近了
But for some reason, only Ren didn't want to get any closer.
え？なんで？
缇亚忒：诶？为什么？
Eh? Why?
ふう
菈琪旭：呼呜
Fuuu
帰ろう
珂朵莉：回去吧
Let's go back.
帰ろう
珂朵莉：回去吧
Let's go back.
レンは何度もそう繰り返した
珂朵莉：莲重复了好几次
Ren repeated that over and over.
だけど私たちは、嫌がるレンを引っ張って、木の下まで近づいてしまった
珂朵莉：但是我们，硬拉着不情愿的奈芙莲，靠近到了树下
But we dragged the reluctant Ren and got close to the tree.
そうしたら、ボトリ、と、何か落ちる音がして
珂朵莉：就在这时，“扑通”一声，有什么东西掉下来了
Then, with a thud, we heard something fall.
枝が揺れなくなった
珂朵莉：树枝不再摇晃了
The branch stopped swaying.
うわああ！
：哇啊啊！
Waaaaah!
全力で走って！早く！
珂朵莉：全速逃跑！快点！
Run as fast as you can! Hurry!
レンが今まで聞いたことのないような声でそう叫んで、
珂朵莉：莲用从未听过的声音那样喊道，
Ren screamed in a voice I'd never heard before
同時に妖精倉庫へ向かって走り出した
珂朵莉：同时向妖精仓库跑去
and started running towards the Fairy Warehouse at the same time.
その尋常じゃない様子に、私とアイセアはレンを追いかけ、
珂朵莉：看到那非同寻常的样子，我和艾瑟雅追着奈芙莲，
Seeing her unusual state, Ithea and I chased after Ren
なんとか妖精倉庫に駆け込んだ
珂朵莉：总算跑进了妖精仓库
and somehow managed to run into the Fairy Warehouse.
なんで走ったんだ？
可蓉：为什么要跑啊？
Why did she run?
私たちもレンにそう聞いたわ
珂朵莉：我们也那样问了奈芙莲
We asked Ren the same thing.
そ、それで？
可蓉：然、然后呢？
A-And?
レンは言った
珂朵莉：奈芙莲说
Ren said...
見えなかったの
奈芙莲：没看见
I didn't see it.
花だか？
可蓉：是花吗？
The flower?
ううん
珂朵莉：不
No.
最初から花なんて咲いてなかった
珂朵莉：从一开始就没有什么花开着
There were no flowers blooming from the start.
レンが見たのは
珂朵莉：奈芙莲看到的是
What Ren saw was...
首を吊った赤毛のトロールの頭
珂朵莉：上吊的红发食人鬼的头
The head of a red-haired troll hanging by its neck.
そして、千切れて落ちた、ナイグラートの胴体が、
珂朵莉：以及，撕裂掉落的，妮戈兰的身体，
And the torn-off body of Nygglatho,
笑いながら追いかけてくる姿
珂朵莉：一边笑着一边追过来的身影
chasing after us while laughing!
ぎゃあああああ！！
：呀啊啊啊啊啊！！
Gyaaaaaah!!
これが、7つ目のお話でした
珂朵莉：这就是，第7个故事了
That was the 7th story.
ちょっとアレンジ加えちゃったけどね
珂朵莉：虽然稍微加了点改编呢
I added a little arrangement, though.
ん？
珂朵莉：嗯？
Hm?
ごめんなさいごめんなさいごめんなさい……
菈琪旭：对不起对不起对不起……
I'm sorry, I'm sorry, I'm sorry...
悪霊退散、悪霊退散、悪霊退散、悪霊退散……
缇亚忒：恶灵退散、恶灵退散、恶灵退散、恶灵退散……
Evil spirits be gone, evil spirits be gone...
ありゃ
珂朵莉：哎呀
Oh my.
さ、さすがクトリ、鬼気迫る語り口だった
潘丽宝：不、不愧是珂朵莉，那口气真是逼真啊
A-As expected of Chtholly, that was some intense storytelling.
お、お、おう
可蓉：噢、噢、噢
Oh, o-oh, yeah.
そんな怖かったかな？
珂朵莉：有那么可怕吗？
Was it that scary?
怖くなんがない！
：不可怕！
It was not scary!
じゃ、最後の蝋燭消そうか
珂朵莉：那，把最后的蜡烛灭了吧
Well then, shall we extinguish the last candle?
う、うん、そ、そうだな
潘丽宝：唔、嗯，是、是啊
Y-Yeah, r-right.
それとも、やっぱりやめとく？
珂朵莉：还是说，果然还是算了吗？
Or, should we stop after all?
いや、私が消す
潘丽宝：不，我来灭
No, I'll do it.
パニバル
可蓉：潘丽宝
Pannibal.
怖くないと言ったら嘘になるかもしれない
潘丽宝：说不害怕可能是骗人的
I'd be lying if I said I wasn't scared.
しかし、恐怖に打ち勝ってこそ、一人前の妖精兵だ
潘丽宝：但是，只有战胜恐惧，才是独当一面的妖精兵
However, overcoming fear is what makes a full-fledged fairy soldier!
ふう
潘丽宝：呼——
Foo.
あー
菈琪旭：啊——
Ah...
うー
缇亚忒：呜——
Ooh...
枕だ
可蓉：是枕头
It's a pillow.
7つの蝋燭全て吹き消した
潘丽宝：7根蜡烛全部吹灭了
All seven candles have been blown out.
これでついに、伝説のお化けが
潘丽宝：这样终于，传说中的妖怪……
Now, finally, the legendary monster...
何も起こらない
可蓉：什么也没发生
Nothing's happening.
あ、よかった
菈琪旭：太好了
Thank goodness.
おかしいな、儀式の段取りは間違ってないはずなんだが
潘丽宝：真奇怪啊，仪式的步骤应该没弄错才对
Strange. The ritual steps shouldn't have been wrong.
あああー
缇亚忒：啊啊啊
Ahhhh!
どうしたのティアット
珂朵莉：怎么了缇亚忒
What's wrong, Tiat?
あ、あの先輩
缇亚忒：那、那个前辈
Uh, Senpai...
なんか廊下から
缇亚忒：走廊那边好像……
Something from the hallway...
え？
珂朵莉：诶？
Eh?
鈴の音？
珂朵莉：铃声？
Sound of bell?
だんだんこの部屋に近づいてくる
可蓉：正渐渐向这房间靠近
It's getting closer to this room.
伝説のお化け、勝負だ！てあー！
潘丽宝：传说中的妖怪，决一胜负吧！喝啊——！
Legendary monster, let's fight! Te-ah!
みゃーお
：喵——
Meow.
ん？
潘丽宝：嗯？
Hm?
おー、猫だ！
可蓉：噢——是猫！
Oh! It's a cat!
猫？
珂朵莉：猫？
A cat?
本当だ
缇亚忒：真的诶
It's true.
あ、その子、パン屋さんのチャロだ
菈琪旭：啊，那孩子，是面包店的查罗
Ah, that's Charo from the bakery.
昼間おじさんが探してたよ
菈琪旭：白天大叔在找它呢
The owner was looking for it during the day.
えー？迷い猫がこんな遠くまで？
珂朵莉：诶——？迷路猫跑了这么远吗？
Eh? A stray cat came all this way?
びっくりした
缇亚忒：吓了一跳
That surprised me.
儀式は完璧だったはずなのに、どこで間違えたのだろうか
潘丽宝：仪式应该很完美才对，到底是哪里出错了呢
The ritual should have been perfect. Where did we go wrong?
本がインチキだったんじゃないかな
可蓉：也许书是骗人的吧
Maybe the book was fake.
よっと
珂朵莉：嘿咻
Hup.
にゃーお
：喵——
Meow.
そういうことかもね
珂朵莉：也许是那样吧
Maybe so.
もう遅いし、今日はおしまいにして、君たちは寝なさい
珂朵莉：已经很晚了，今天就到此为止，你们快睡吧
It's late now. Let's call it a night. You girls go to sleep.
この子は私が預かるから
珂朵莉：这孩子就由我来照顾
I'll take care of this little one.
仕方ないな
潘丽宝：没办法呢
Can't be helped.
ラキシュ、今日一緒に寝よう
缇亚忒：菈琪旭，今天一起睡吧
Lakhesh, let's sleep together tonight.
うん
菈琪旭：嗯
Yeah.
私も
可蓉：我也要
Me too.
私もだ
潘丽宝：我也要
Me too.
もう、ベッドぎゅうぎゅうになっちゃうよ
菈琪旭：真是的，床都要被挤爆了啦
Jeez, the bed's gonna be packed tight.
はあ、やっと寝てくれたか
珂朵莉：哈啊，终于睡了啊
Sigh, they finally went to sleep.
ん、今日は廊下が妙に肌寒いな
珂朵莉：唔，今天的走廊莫名地冷呢
Umm, the hallway is strangely chilly today.
まるで真冬みたい
珂朵莉：简直像深冬一样
It's just like midwinter.
あ、ほら、暴れちゃダメ
珂朵莉：啊，不准乱动
Oh, don't struggle.
あれ？
珂朵莉：啊咧？
Huh?
君の首は
珂朵莉：你的脖子……
Your neck...
鈴が付いてない？
珂朵莉：没有装铃铛？
Has no bell?
て事は、さっきの鈴の音…
珂朵莉：那，刚才的铃声…
So, the sound of bell just now...
ぎゃああああ！
珂朵莉：咿呀啊啊啊啊！
Gyaaaaaah!